Finding Aid for M-Pathways Project (University of Michigan) records, 1996-2006
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Organizational
  - Smithsonian Museum Technology Innovation Award Nomination, not dated (Box 3)
  - Software End User License and Services Agreement May 1995 (Box 3)
  - Space Management Software February 1996 (Box 3)
  - Space Management System 1996 (Box 3)
  - Standards for Project Planning and Reporting 1996 (Box 3)
  - Strategic Data Plan circa 1993-1995
    - Executive Overview October 1993 (Box 3)
    - Report March 1995 (Box 3)
  - Structural Validation Process, 1996 (Box 3)
  - Archivist's Documentation on Strategic Data Plan Document Library Database September 2000 (Box 3)
  - Strategic Data Plan Documentation Library circa 1995-1996
    - Alumni/Development Process
      - Gift Endowment Performance project definition (Box 3)
      - Gift/Grant Project definition (Box 3)
      - Gift/Pledge processing Project definition (Box 3)
    - Data Infrastructure project, Rule, Regulation, Policy and Procedure (Box 3)
    - Financial Resources Project
      - Billing and Receivable Management Project definition (Box 3)
      - Budgeting Project definition (Box 3)
      - Cost Reimbursement Project definition (Box 3)
      - Economic Event Project definition (Box 3)
      - Environmental Health and Occupational Safety Management (Box 3)
      - Incidents Tracking Project definition (Box 3)
      - Investment Project definition (Box 3)
      - Financial Reporting Project definition (Box 3)
      - Payment Management Project definition (Box 3)
      - Procurement
        - Inventory Management Project definition (Box 3)
        - Procurement Project definition (Box 3)
        - Receiving Project definition (Box 3)
      - Risk management Project definition (Box 3)
      - Security Project definition (Box 3)
    - Human Resources Project
      - Benefits Administration Project definition (Box 3)
      - Claims Management Project definition (Box 3)
      - Flexible Benefits Project definition (Box 3)
      - Human Resources Project definition (Box 3)
      - Person and Organization Project definition (Box 3)
    - Physical Resources Project
      - Asset Management Project definition (Box 3)
      - Construction Projects Project definition (Box 3)
      - Maintenance Management Project definition (Box 3)
      - Parking Management Project definition (Box 3)
      - Space Management Project definition (Box 3)
      - Transportation Management Project definition (Box 3)
    - Projects Miscellaneous, Housing Project definition
      - Quality Improvement Project, Credentials Training Project definition (Box 3)
      - Quality Improvement Project, Events Planning, Marketing, and Administration Project definition (Box 3)
    - Student Administration Project
      - Curriculum and Degree Management: Course Approval Request Project definition (Box 3)
      - Curriculum Database Project definition (Box 3)
      - Curriculum: Data Infrastructure Project Student Administration Project, Degree Audit Project definition (Box 3)
      - Electronic Application Project (Box 3)
      - Electronic Viewbook Project definition (Box 3)
      - Enrollment Management Project definition (Box 3)
      - Graduate and Professional Enrollment (Box 3)
      - Food Service Management Project definition (Box 3)
      - Professional Enrollment Project definition (Box 3)
      - Student Enrollment Transfer Credit Project definition (Box 3)
      - Student Enrollment Undergraduate Enrollment Project definition (Box 3)
      - Student Finance Project definition (Box 3)
      - Student Tracking: Academic Record Project definition (Box 3)
      - Tuition and Fees Project definition (Box 3)
    - Student Life Project
      - Career Development and Placement Project (Box 3)
      - Co-curricular Program Management (Box 3)
      - Counseling Management Project definition (Box 3)
      - Student Activity Project definition (Box 3)
    - Technical Project
      - Analytical and Forecasting Tools Project definition (Box 3)
      - Conferencing/Groupware Project definition (Box 3)
      - Electronic Calendaring Project definition (Box 3)
      - Electronic Mail Project definition (Box 3)
      - Electronic TimeKeeping Project definition (Box 3)
      - EDI/EFT Project definition (Box 3)
      - Multimedia and Hypertext Project definition (Box 3)
      - Object Technology Project definition (Box 3)
      - Remote/Local Printing Project definition (Box 3)
      - Security-Authorization /Authentication Project definition (Box 3)
      - Technology Architecture including co-existence (Box 3)
  - Strategic Data Plan Implementation Plan, 1997 (Box 3)
  - Summary of Campus Feedback on Scope and Structure document June 1999 (Box 3)
  - Team Charge Statements 1996-1997 (Box 3)
  - University of Michigan PeopleSoft (UMPS) Meeting Minutes 1996-1998 (Box 3)
- Student Administration
  The Student Administration series (5 linear feet) is divided into two subseries: Student Beta Project and Topical. The Student Beta Project subseries provides a comprehensive view of Michigan's involvement with PeopleSoft to develop a student administration system for the higher education market. The subseries includes electronic mail (print-outs) from other "Beta Partners" in the Big Ten Conference. The electronic mail captures the initial set-up struggles each of the schools experienced in undertaking this massive project. The correspondence also shows the collaborative efforts between Big Ten schools and the use of electronic mail as a tool to collect and discuss shared problems with the design of the PeopleSoft systems. The subseries also includes the system prerelease documentation, as well as software documentation.
  - Student Beta Project
    The Student Beta Project subseries provides a comprehensive view of Michigan's involvement with PeopleSoft to develop a student administration system for the higher education market. The subseries includes electronic mail (print-outs) from other "Beta Partners" in the Big Ten Conference. The electronic mail captures the initial set-up struggles each of the schools experienced in undertaking this massive project. The correspondence also shows the collaborative efforts between Big Ten schools and the use of electronic mail as a tool to collect and discuss shared problems with the design of the PeopleSoft systems. The subseries also includes the system prerelease documentation, as well as software documentation.
    - Archivist's Documentation on Big 10 Database November 2000 (Box 4)
    - Beta Project Staff discussion (electronic mail) 1996 (Box 4)
    - Big Ten Discussion (electronic mail) 1993-1995, 2 folders (Box 4)
    - PeopleSoft circa 1993-1995
      - Twelve months of Beta (Box 4)
      - Account Information (Box 4)
      - Academic Structure (Box 4)
      - Admissions (Box 4)
      - Archiving (Box 4)
      - Background Information (Box 4)
      - Beta Partners (Box 4)
      - Beta Partners Leads (Box 4)
    - PeopleSoft: Beta Team Meeting 1995-1997
      - March 6, 1997 (Box 4)
      - February 20, 1997 (Box 4)
      - January 9, 1997 (Box 4)
      - December 20, 1996 (Box 4)
      - November 14, 1996 (Box 4)
      - October 31, 1996 (Box 4)
      - October 17, 1996 (Box 4)
      - October 3, 1996 (Box 4)
      - September 26, 1996 (Box 4)
      - September 12, 1996 (Box 4)
      - September 5, 1996 (Box 4)
      - August 22, 1996 (Box 4)
      - August 8, 1996 (Box 4)
      - August 1, 1996 (Box 4)
      - July 18, 1996 (Box 4)
      - June 13, 1996 (Box 4)
      - May 16, 1996 (Box 4)
      - May 9, 1996 (Box 4)
      - May 2, 1996 (Box 4)
      - April 18, 1996 (Box 4)
      - April 4, 1996 (Box 4)
      - March 28, 1996 (Box 4)
      - March 21, 1996 (Box 4)
      - March 14, 1996 (Box 4)
      - March 7, 1996 (Box 4)
      - February 29, 1996 (Box 4)
      - February 22, 1996 (Box 4)
      - February 15, 1996 (Box 4)
      - February 1, 1996 (Box 4)
      - January 25, 1996 (Box 4)
      - January 18, 1996 (Box 4)
      - January 11, 1996 (Box 4)
      - December 14, 1995 (Box 4)
      - November 30, 1995 (Box 4)
      - November 16, 1995 (Box 4)
      - November 2, 1995 (Box 4)
    - PeopleSoft: Beta Team Meeting (Box 4)
    - PeopleSoft circa 1995-1997
      - Briefing (Box 4)
      - Campus Community (Box 4)
      - CD-ROMS (Box 4)
      - Campus Community Name/Address (Box 4)
      - Campus Community X.500 (Box 4)
      - Co-Development Team (Box 4)
      - Co-Development Team January 9, 1997 (Box 4)
      - Communications (Box 4)
      - Communication Liaisons (Box 4)
      - April 1996 Conference Budget/Timelines (Box 4)
      - April 1996 Conference Miscellaneous (Box 4)
      - Contract Open Horizons, Security (Box 4)
      - Contract-Training (Box 4)
      - Consulting Contracts (Box 4)
      - Correspondence (Box 4)
      - Core Process Management Team (CPMT) (Box 4)
      - Cross Project Dependencies (Box 4)
      - Current Systems Inventory (Box 4)
      - Contract (Box 4)
      - Data Integration (Box 4)
      - Database Instances (Box 4)
      - Distributed Computing Environment (DCE) (Box 4)
      - Debriefing (Box 4)
    - PeopleSoft circa 1996
      - Documentation
        - Academic Advisement Requirements July 1996 (Box 5)
        - Admissions Processing July 1996 (Box 5)
        - Campus Community Business Processes July 1996 (Box 5)
        - Designing Admissions July 1996 (Box 5)
        - Designing Financial Aid July 1996 (Box 5)
        - Designing Student Records July 1996 (Box 5)
        - Financial Aid Business Processes July 1996 (Box 5)
        - Student Financials July 1996 (Box 5)
        - Student Financials Business Processes July 1996 (Box 5)
        - Student Financials, Interfacing to Financial Systems July 1996 (Box 5)
        - Student Progress Assessment Base Data Model Overview July 1996 (Box 5)
        - Student Records Business Processes July 1996 (Box 5)
      - Executive Overview: Structured Techniques and Case circa 1987 (Box 5)
      - Financial Aid circa 1995 (Box 5)
      - Financial Aid perspective on joint session and prep questions for April 1997 beta conference (Box 5)
      - Functional Scope Documents circa 1996, 2 folders (Box 5)
      - Functional Scope Gap Documents December 1996 (Box 5)
      - Gap Information November 1997 (Box 5)
      - Hardware/Software Requirements (Box 5)
      - High Level Student Data Model July 1993 (Box 5)
      - Housing circa 1995 (Box 5)
      - Implementation Team meetings circa 1996 (Box 5)
      - Implementation Plan 1995 (Box 5)
      - Implementation Team 1995-1996 (Box 5)
      - Information Technology Division (ITD) Resources (Box 5)
      - Institutional Research/Reporting circa 1996 (Box 5)
      - Management Structure, ca 1995 (Box 5)
      - Missing Functionality circa 1996 (Box 5)
      - Navigation Guides 1996
        - Admissions (Box 5)
        - Campus Community (Box 5)
        - Financial Aid (Box 5)
        - Student Financials (Box 5)
        - Student Records (Box 5)
      - NCAA circa 1996 (Box 5)
      - Open Applications Group (OAG) circa 1996 (Box 5)
      - Pilot Prep circa 1996 (Box 5)
      - Preliminary circa 1996 (Box 5)
      - Prerelease V3 Documentation undated
        - Admissions Processing (Box 5)
        - Assigning Checklists (Box 5)
        - Campus Community Business Processes (Box 5)
        - Designing Campus Community (Box 5)
        - Designing Financial Aid (Box 5)
        - Designing Student Records (Box 5)
        - Student Financials (Box 5)
        - Student Financials Business Processes (Box 5)
    - PeopleSoft circa 1995-1996
      - Prerelease V3 Documentation Student Records Business Processes (Box 6)
      - Process Management Lead Team (PLMT) (Box 6)
      - Process Methodology (Box 6)
      - Product Deliverables Update May 24, 1996 (Box 6)
      - Presentations (Box 6)
      - Project Management (Box 6)
      - Records and Registration and Academic Advising (RARA) (Box 6)
      - Reporting (Box 6)
      - Request for Information (Box 6)
      - Requirements Gathering (Box 6)
      - Room Scheduling (Box 6)
      - Security (Box 6)
      - Committee on Release of Student Information (Box 6)
      - James Madison University Trip September, 1995 (Box 6)
    - Software Documentation circa 1996
      - Admissions Business Processes October 1996 (Box 6)
      - Campus Community Business Processes October 1996 (Box 6)
      - Designing Campus Community October 1996 (Box 6)
      - Designing Financial Aid October 1996 (Box 6)
      - Designing Student Financials October 1996 (Box 6)
      - Financial Aid Business Processes October 1996 (Box 6)
      - Student Financials Business Processes October 1996 (Box 6)
      - Student Records Business Processes October 1996 (Box 6)
      - Student Financials Process December 1996 (Box 6)
      - Student Records Process December 1996 (Box 6)
      - Designing Student Records December 1996 (Box 6)
      - Financial Aid Process December 1996 (Box 6)
      - Designing Financials Aid December 1996 (Box 6)
      - Designing Student Financials December 1996 (Box 6)
      - Designing Student Records December 1996 (Box 6)
      - Designing Admissions December 1996 (Box 6)
      - Designing Campus Community December 1996 (Box 6)
    - Student Information Systems (SIS) Teams 1996 (Box 6)
    - Strategic Data Plan (SDP) March 1995 (Box 6)
    - Student Financial (Beta release 6) 1996 (Box 6)
    - Student Records Program (Student Data Subgroup) 1993-1996 (Box 6)
    - Student Systems Development Project Plan May 1995 (Box 6)
    - Support Model 1996 (Box 6)
    - Technical 1996 (Box 6)
    - Technical Infrastructure 1996 (Box 6)
    - Training Information 1995-1996 (Box 6)
    - Travel Poems 1995-1996 (Box 6)
    - University of Michigan PeopleSoft (UMPS) 1996 (Box 6)
    - Western Ontario 1996 (Box 6)
  - Topical
    The Topical subseries focuses mainly on the implementation phase of the student system modules. The subseries is reflective of the methodology used for all five system implementations. Evidence of the methodology can be found in the documentation of current business processes and "To Be" process flows. The subseries includes module scope documents and data entity diagrams. Researchers interested in further examination of the methodology used by the project, as well as the design of the system may want to consult the Student Administration System SAS design deliverables database and the Student Information System (SIS) Pathways database located on CD-ROM (Box 1). The SAS design deliverables database holds the documents that reflect the first phase of the project methodology, the Design Phase. The organization of the database reflects the structure of the methodology. The structure of the methodology follows a sequence of activities, tasks, and deliverables. Note that each level has a corresponding numerical identifier, thus, all documents are referenced by this number. Deliverables in the design phase include identification of the Business Objectives for the Student System, a survey of the Information Needs, and Profiles of the Current Systems, Business Processes, Interfaces, Reports, and Users. The design phase documentation provides a very focused snapshot of the work processes and procedures in place in the administrative offices at the university in the late 1990s. The SIS Pathways database includes meeting minutes from the functional lead and technical team meetings, discussion documents on the campus community module, proposed table values for the academic advising and admissions modules, and discussion documents related to the design of the web interface for student registration.
    - Academic Affairs Student Administration Core Process Unit Transition Team; Scope and Structure February 1999 (Box 7)
    - Academic Policy Committee 1998-1999 (Box 7)
    - Admissions and Recruiting circa 1996-1997
      - Cross Dependencies discussion 1996 (Box 7)
      - Data Mapping 1997 (Box 7)
      - Datawarehouse 1997 (Box 7)
      - Design Discussion (electronic mail) 1996-1997 (Box 7)
      - External Organization 1997 (Box 7)
      - Functional Requirements 1997 (Box 7)
      - Future Process Flows, Academic Outreach 1997 (Box 7)
      - Future Process Flows, Transfer Credit 1997 (Box 7)
      - Future Reports 1997 (Box 7)
      - Issues 1997-1998 (Box 7)
      - Transfer Credit Meeting Minutes 1996 (Box 7)
      - Gap Listing 1996-1997 (Box 7)
      - Potential Modifications 1996-1997 (Box 7)
      - Recruiting System Information Packet (Box 7)
      - SAT Test Score Processing (Box 7)
      - Student Characteristics Database (SCDB) 1993-1996 (Box 7)
      - Transfer Credit Process 1996-1997 (Box 7)
      - Transfer Credit Focus Group 1996 (Box 7)
    - Admissions Data Roster September 1998 (Box 7)
    - Campus Community Data Security June 1999 (Box 7)
    - Campus Impact Statement: Decentralization Plan May 1999 (Box 7)
    - Communications, Comments, and Checklists discussion 1997 (Box 7)
    - Conversion Approach Memo December 1997 (Box 7)
    - Course/Class/Facility Conversion Plan February 1999 (Box 7)
    - Course Tools Project September 1999 (Box 7)
    - Current Business Processes circa 1997
      - Academic Advising June 1997 (Box 7)
      - Academic Advising/Academic Actions June 1997 (Box 7)
      - Academic Milestone Management January 1997 (Box 7)
      - Academic Program Management June 1997 (Box 7)
      - Academic Structure Program Maintenance June 1997 (Box 7)
      - Class Management June 1997 (Box 7)
      - Course Management January 1997 (Box 7)
      - Enrollment June 1997 (Box 7)
      - Evaluate Curriculum Effectiveness January 1997 (Box 7)
      - Graduation June 1997 (Box 7)
      - Official Reporting January 1997 (Box 7)
      - Registration January 1997 (Box 7)
      - Student Group Tracking January 1997 (Box 7)
      - Student Records-Grades June 1997 (Box 7)
      - Transcripts June 1997 (Box 7)
      - University Honors April 1997 (Box 7)
      - Verification/Certification June 1997 (Box 7)
    - Data Conversion Interface Tool 1997 (Box 7)
    - Data Elements: Recruiting and Admissions 1998 (Box 7)
    - Data Models: Student Administration 1998 (Box 7)
    - Decentralization Plan 1999 (Box 7)
    - End User Support Plan 1999 (Box 7)
    - Faculty Outreach Strategy for Student Administration 1999 (Box 7)
    - FERPA discussion 1997 (Box 7)
    - Flint/Dearborn Student Administration development 1997 (Box 7)
    - Functional Lead Meeting Agendas and Minutes 1996-1997 (Box 7)
    - Functional Requirements, various dates (Box 7)
    - Functions Summary March 1996
      - Academic Advisement (Box 7)
      - Admission and Recruiting (Box 7)
      - Campus Community (Box 7)
      - Student Financials and Financial Aid (Box 7)
      - Student Records (Box 7)
    - Future Business Process circa 1998
      - Academic Program Management 1998 (Box 7)
      - Academic Structure Management 1998 (Box 7)
      - Assign Appointments 1998 (Box 7)
      - Class Enrollment 1998 (Box 7)
      - Class List Production 1998 (Box 7)
      - Class Management 1998 (Box 7)
      - Course management 1998 (Box 7)
      - Grades 1998, 2 folders (Box 7)
      - Overrides 1998 (Box 7)
      - Permission to Enroll 1998 (Box 7)
      - Re-registration 1997 (Box 7)
      - Student Records, Curriculum, and Academic Advising Overview February 1997 (Box 8)
      - Term Activation 1998 (Box 8)
      - Term Withdrawal 1998 (Box 8)
      - Wait Lists 1998 (Box 8)
    - Future Business Process and Process Flows circa 1998
      - Academic Advising (Box 8)
      - Academic Honors (Box 8)
      - Academic Milestone Tracking (Box 8)
      - Evaluate Curriculum effectiveness (Box 8)
      - Graduation (Box 8)
      - Master to Doctoral level change (Box 8)
      - Official Reporting (Box 8)
      - Student Group Tracking (Box 8)
      - Transcript Processing (Box 8)
      - Verification/Certification (Box 8)
    - Gap Analysis Reports for Student Administration 1996 (Box 8)
    - Implementation Scope Delay Plan for Student Administration June 1999 (Box 8)
    - Inventory of Current Reports and Ad Hoc Environment Usage June 1997 (Box 8)
    - Inventory of Current Student Administration Systems June 1997 (Box 8)
    - Legacy System Shut Down Plan 1999 (Box 8)
    - PeopleSoft circa 1996
      - Account Manager meeting 1996 (Box 8)
      - Admissions Business Process 1996 (Box 8)
    - PeopleSoft version 6.0 PeopleBook 1997 (Box 8)
    - PeopleSoft version 7.5 upgrade: Guide to changes for Recruiting and Admissions May 1999 (Box 8)
    - PeopleSoft version 7.5: Student Administration Atlas of Business Processes 1999 (Box 8)
    - Policy and Practice Resolution Structure for the M-Pathways Project November 1999 (Box 8)
    - Policy, Practice, Implementation Team 1997-1999 (Box 8)
    - Project Charter January 1999 (Box 8)
    - Purge Policy: Prospects and Applicants May 1999 (Box 8)
    - Recruiting Conference Room Pilot discussion (electronic mail) 1997 (Box 8)
    - Recruiting and Admissions Impacts: Reference Guide, 2000 (Box 8)
    - School of Information 530 MIND Group Project 1997 (Box 8)
    - Security Approach for Student Administration, 1999 (Box 8)
    - SIS Design Partners Meeting 1996 (Box 8)
    - Student Administration System circa 1996-1999
      - Business Process Re-engineering 1999 (Box 8)
      - Co-Development Discussion (electronic mail),1996 (Box 8)
      - Critical Gaps List 1996 (Box 8)
      - Database (Located on CD-ROM, CD BOX 1) (Box 8)
      - Enrollment Deposit discussion 1996 (Box 8)
      - Events Management discussion 1997 (Box 8)
      - Facilities Tables Set-Up 1996 (Box 8)
      - Field of Study discussion 1997 (Box 8)
      - Mass Change undated (Box 8)
      - Organization, Core Process Unit Scope and Structure 1999 (Box 8)
      - Physical Data Model 1997 (Box 8)
      - Related University Committees and Groups 1999 (Box 8)
      - Scope documents various dates (Box 8)
      - Security Administration 1997 (Box 8)
      - Review of Strategic Data Plan March 1998 (Box 8)
      - Resource Analysis Reports, various dates (Box 8)
      - Tables by Module February, 1999 (Box 8)
      - Testing Approach Memo April 1998 (Box 8)
    - Student Entry Redesign Project Working Group 1997-1999 (Box 8)
    - Student Implementation System (SIS) database (Located on CD-ROM, CD BOX 1) (Box 8)
    - Student Implementation System Design Partners Meeting 1996 (Box 8)
    - Student Implementation Team Agendas and Meeting Minutes 1996-1998 (Box 8)
    - Student Records Conceptual Data Models May 1998 (Box 8)
    - Student Records Overall Process Map April 1997 (Box 8)
    - Student Registration System: Wolverine Access February 2000
      - "To Be" Process Flows, various dates (Box 8)
      - Enrollment, various dates (Box 8)
      - Grades, various dates (Box 8)
    - Transcript Order Entry System (TOES) Issues List 1999 (Box 8)
    - Universal Algorithm, Inc. 1997 (Box 8)
    - Visiting Scholars in the M-Pathways System 1999 (Box 8)
    - Work Plan Assumptions 1997 (Box 8)
- Technology Management